Sonal Kumari

San Antonio, TX Phone No-210-9315100 Email | LinkedIn

PROFILE

Data Analytics Specialist with 11+ years of extensive experience in Insurance, Banking and Telecommunication domain with Data Science and Business Analytics, producing data driven insights and recommendation for business - worked as a team leader and an individual contributor.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Decision Science Analyst, United Services Automobile Association ("USAA")-Contract; San Antonio, TX — 2018-Present

Developed and managed Analytics reports and dashboards for Auto Experience and Data Governance Program of USAA, which involved statistical analysis on raw data, querying data from different data sources such as Hadoop, IBM DB2, Oracle and Netezza, using SQL, pandas, numpy, pandas_profiling and other python packages and building reports and dashboards in Tableau and Ms Excel.

Performed Web Analytics on the Auto Experience web data by analyzing web users' engagement on the website, customer pathing, traffic sources, content effectiveness, and translated web data into actionable metrics like conversion pain points.

Performed analysis on Insurance and Banking datasets hosted on Cloud Environment using AWS Analytics Ecosystem including S3 Bucket, AWS Python interface Boto3, SageMaker, Athena and QuickSight and EC2 instances and Jupyter notebook, providing insight on the data quality issues and adherence to regulatory and data security standards.

Digital Analytics Manager, Sprint Corporation; Overland Park, KS — 2017-2018

Managed and led project related to Adobe Analytics implementation by working alongside business owners/partners, development team, web/Marketing team in an Agile environment.

Built technical specification in javascript to gather web traffic information on a eCommerce Site and supported implementation of the analytics script on the website also ensured accuracy of the collected web data by validating analytics tags in lab/QA and production environment.

Trained and mentored product owners to develop dashboards and reports integrating digital data sources and establish data alerts on Adobe Analytics for receiving real time notifications on major shifts in metrics.

Marketing Data Analyst, United Services Automobile Association ("USAA")-Contract; San Antonio, TX — 2015-2017

Integrated customer's data with Social Media campaign results from Facebook and Twitter Ads Manager using SQL, SAS, Tableau and performed customer centric deep dive analysis and generated data driven insights and recommendations for optimizing campaigns based on customer demographics and profile.

Identified strategic metrics to measure success of the Social Media Campaigns and built user interactive dashboards to monitor and visualize the performance of the Facebook and Twitter Marketing Ads on weekly and monthly basis.

BI Developer, Tata Consultancy Services; United Services Automobile Association ("USAA")- Contract; India — 2010-2015

Analyzed the product acquisition flow for various Banking and Insurance products on digital channels and generated insights on the product acquisition pain points.

Performed cross channel analysis and analyzed multiple touch points of a user across digital and offline channels and generated insights and recommendation to optimize users' experience on these channels.

EDUCATION

SASTRA University, India—Bachelor of Technology (Electrical and Electronics) with distinction, 2010

SKILLS

Python, SQL, HQL, SAS Programming, SAS Macro, MS Excel,Oracle10g, IBM DB2, NETEZZA, Hadoop, Amazon S3,Adobe Analytics, Power BI, IBM IGC, Tableau Desktop 2021.1, AWS Glue, Amazon Athena, Amazon QuickSight, Amazon SageMaker, Anaconda, Jupyter Notebook

CERTIFICATIONS

Base SAS Programming, Statistical Concepts, Model Thinking, Google Adwords, Tableau Desktop Specialist